《老友记》前情介绍：
Previously on Friends:
工作的事怎么样
How did the job stuff go?
他给了我一份工作
He offered me one!
你知道吗
You know what?
这时候该来一瓶以色列的佳酿
This calls for a bottle of lsrael's finest!
工作地点在巴黎
The job is in Paris.
天啊  你们说话呀
Oh, God, please, somebody say something.
如果你接受这份工作
So if you take this job,
你将要搬去巴黎吗
you'll be moving to Paris?
难道是乘飞机上下班
Or facing a bitch of a commute.
我知道  这是大事
I know, it's huge,
我感到恐惧
and it's scary
而且离你们那么那么的遥远
and it's really far away from you guys.
可是这对我是一个很好的机会
But this is such an incredible opportunity for me.
我还跟他们说明了艾玛的情况
I've already told them about our situation with Emma...
他们答应尽力给予我方便
...and they said they'll do whatever we need to make us feel comfortable.
我可以回来看望她
I mean, I'll fly back and forth,
你也可以带她去看望我
they'll fly you out.
满足我们任何要求
Anything we want.
我老板答应给我的睡房
My boss said I might be getting a new lamp
买一盏新的台灯
in my cubicle.
好的  试试看吧
All right. We'll work it out.
谢谢  谢谢
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
这是你渴望的吗
You sure this is what you want?
我相信是
I think it is.
怎么了
What's going on?
我得到一份很棒的工作
I got a really incredible job offer.
-太好了  -为你高兴
- Hey, great! All right! - Good for you!
-是在巴黎   -什么
- It's in Paris. - What?
不...
No...
不  发生太多改变了
No, too much is changing, okay?
首先  菲比结婚了
First Phoebe getting married.
恭喜
Congratulations.
然后这两个家伙要搬到
And then these two move in to
郊区那所讨厌的房子
a stupid house in the stupid suburbs.
嘿  今天下午你还说会支持的
Earlier, you said you'd be supportive.
我变来变去的  不能相信我
It comes and goes. I wouldn't trust it!
伙计们
You guys, this is really,
这对我十分十分重要
really important to me.
如果你们尝试接受
It means a lot
我会很感激的
if you could try to get onboard.
我们当然会  恭喜你
Of course we can. Congratulations.
谢谢
Thank you.
乔伊
Joey?
我只抱留在美国的那些人
No, my hugs are reserved for people staying in America!
乔伊  这对我...
Joey, it would mean--
不  要去法国的人别靠近我
No! Get your France-going arms away from me!
你没事儿吧
Are you okay with this?
实际上我感到伤心
Well, it makes me feel sad, but--
我是在问罗斯
Talking to Ross.
知道了
I see.
瑞秋去了另一个国家
Rachel moving to another country?
不能每天看到她
Not being able to see her every day?
我怎么会不难过
How could I be okay with this?
我们又能怎么样
But what are we gonna do?
她需要这份工作
She really needs this job.
如果拉夫·劳伦公司请她回去
Do you think if Ralph Lauren offered her her old job back,
她会愿意吗
she would take it?
这怎么可能
How's that gonna happen?
你就是这么使用你的三个魔法愿望的吗
Is this the best way to use one of your three magic wishes?
也许  我也不知道
Like, I don't know,
我能跟她的老板谈谈
I could talk to her boss. Yeah.
对  我跟他在圣诞派对见过面
I met him at that Christmas party.
我们很投缘
I mean, we really hit it off.
是一直管你叫罗恩的那个家伙吗
The guy who kept calling you "Ron"?
我没说我们好成兄弟了
I didn't say we were brothers!
《老友记》  第十季  第15集  艾丝特尔死了
Friends S10E15 The One Where Estelle Dies
嘿  菲比
Hey, Phoebe. Hey.
嘿
Hi.
在我们打算买的那座房子旁边
The house next door to the one
有一座房子也在出售
that we're buying just went on the market.
我想去看看
I wanna take a look at it,
可钱德勒不愿意
but Chandler doesn't.
我们明天就签约了
We close escrow tomorrow.
再看其它房子只会迷惑自己
Seeing another house can only confuse us.
我们很容易感到迷惑
We're easily confused.
我们并不机灵
We're not very bright.
那如果它比我们的更好呢
But what if it's better than ours?
至少应该看看
Shouldn't we look?
你怎么看  菲比
What do you think, Pheebs?
我觉得你穿这件衬衣
Well, I think that shirt makes you look like
像雪糕餐厅的服务员
you should work at a Baskin-Robbins.
信不信由你...
Anyway....
乔伊的经理人是艾丝特尔·伦纳德吗
Hey, isn't Joey's agent Estelle Leonard?
对.
Yeah.
-她死了  -真的吗
- She died. - You're kidding!
-真糟糕   -是的  在上个星期六
- That's terrible. - Yeah, last Saturday.
哇  她是第一个独自驾机
Wow! She was the first black man
飞越大西洋的黑人男性
to fly solo across the Atlantic!
哦  等等  我看串行了
Wait a minute, I read the wrong one.
哦
Oh, yeah?
对  是那个经纪人
Yeah, she was just an agent.
乔伊肯定感到很难过
Joey's gonna be so upset.
是的  他一直希望成为
I know. He always wanted to be
第一个独自驾机飞越大西洋的黑人男性
the first black man to cross the Atlantic.
我们不能让乔伊知道这件事
We cannot tell Joey about this.
一切都在改变
He's already flipping out
他都快要发疯了
about everything changing.
不能再刺激他了
This'll push him over the edge.
你真的认为我们不应该告诉他吗
You don't think we should tell him?
至少暂时不说
Not for a while.
给他几天
Let's just give him a few days
先消化已经发生了的事
to get used to everything else.
如果他从报纸上看到呢
What if he reads the paper?
除非是八卦的史努比告诉查理·布朗
Unless Snoopy says it to Charlie Brown,
否则就没问题
I think we're okay.
有什么事吗
May I help you?
我是瑞秋·格林的朋友
Yeah. I'm a friend of Rachel Green's.
我们两年前在圣诞派对上见过面
Actually, we met at the Christmas party about two years ago.
-哦  是唐   -差不多  是罗恩
- Oh, right. Don? - Close. Ron.
有什么能帮忙的吗
Well, what can I do for you?
想了解一下
Well, I'm here to see
能不能恢复瑞秋的工作
if you'll give Rachel her job back.
是她让你来的吗
Did she ask you to come here and do this?
不  如果你同意了
First I have to get you to agree...
我还要问问她是否愿意回来
...then we'll see if she wants to come back.
哇  这真吸引人
Wow, that is tempting.
她很喜欢这份工作
She loved her job here.
实际上  你找不到比她更好的人选
Let's face it, you're not gonna find anyone...
是这样吗
...who did it as well as she did. Isn't that true?
-是很不错   -我真没料到
- She is good. - I took a shot there.
可是  很抱歉  我无能为力
But I'm sorry, there's nothing I can do.
事实是  我不想出力
Oh, that's not true. There's nothing I want to do.
好的
I see.
非常谢谢
Thanks very much.
-是你儿子吗   -对  他叫罗斯
- Is this your son? - Yeah, his name is Ross.
怎么了
What?
没什么  跟罗恩发音很接近嘛
Nothing, it's just that it's close to Ron.
这小罗斯有可能对恐龙有兴趣吗
Does little Ross like dinosaurs, by any chance?
是的  他老是说起  那又怎么样
Yeah, they're all he talks about. Why?
他是否愿意
How would he like to
和我到自然历史博物馆
come with me to the Museum of Natural History...
在其他人都离开之后
...after everyone else has left,
就剩我们两个
just the two of us...
他想摸哪里就摸哪里
...and he can touch anything he wants?
我说的话  我自己也听到了  有歧义了
I just heard it how you must have heard it, and that's not good.
让我再说一遍   我是古生物学家
Let me start again. I'm a paleontologist.
你也可以在场  摸的只会是骨头...化石
You'll be there with us, and the touching refers only to bones-- fossils!
你真的可以安排到吗
You could really arrange that?
如果你能让瑞秋回来  那就这么定了
You let Rachel come back and it's done.
我想  让瑞秋回来  不见得就是坏事
I guess having Rachel back wouldn't be the worst thing in the world.
太好了  十分感谢
Yes! Thank you! This is great! Thank you so much.
我保证  这是你的孩子会高兴死的
I swear, your kid's gonna have the time of his life.
太好了  我对他挺担心的
That's great. I worry about little Ross.
他老是捧着书本
He's always reading,
收集石头  完全被恐龙给迷住了
collecting rocks and he's obsessed with dinosaurs.
他会正常的
He'll be fine!
- 嘿  菲比  - 嘿
- Hey, Pheebs. - Hey.
你怎么了
Everything okay?
我在生我经纪人的气
I'm just mad at my agent.
艾丝特尔  为什么
Estelle? Why?
有一部电视电影 其中的角色很合适我演
There's a part in this TV movie that I would be perfect for...
她没有推荐我去  她最好有个好的借口
...and I didn't even get put up for it. She better have a good reason.
我想她有的
I'm guessing she does.
我想听听  她老是这样
Well, I wanna hear it, because she keeps doing this.
噢  等等  我要先走了
No, wait, wait, wait! All right, I gotta go.
答应我  等一会再打给她
Just listen. Promise me that you will wait a minute before you call her.
为什么
Well, okay. Why?
因为  朋友之间的诺言  从不需要有原因
Because a promise between friends means never having to give a reason.
我喜欢这句话
I love that saying!
-嗨   -乔伊  我是艾丝特尔
- Hello? - Joey, it's Estelle.
我正想打电话给你  真古怪
I was just gonna call you. That's weird.
这是巧合  但是可信
It's a little coincidental, but believable.
我想你肯定想知道
Listen, I'm sure you're wondering
我为什么没有安排你
why I didn't get you...
为那部电视电影试镜
...an audition for that TV movie.
是的  确实是的
Yeah, actually I am.
我想我失职了
I guess I dropped the ball there.
就这样
That's it?
我最近老是失职
You know, it seems like all you do lately is drop the ball.
不要这么和我说话
Don't take that tone with me.
你以为自己是谁
Who do you think you are?
阿兰·莱蒙
Alan Lemon,
第一个独自驾机飞越大西洋的黑人男性
the first black man to fly solo across the Atlantic?
听我说  你是我的经纪人
No, look, all I'm saying is you're my agent...
但是你没有为我争取到试镜机会
...and you're not getting me any auditions
我受够了
and I'm tired of it.
你这样说什么意思
What are you saying?
我意思是  不能再这样了  艾丝特尔
I'm saying that this isn't working for me anymore, okay, Estelle?
你被解雇了  再见
You're fired. Goodbye.
噢  艾丝特尔这个星期真倒霉
Man, tough week for Estelle.
-嗨  -嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
艾玛把这忘在我那了
Emma left her stuffed T. Rex at my house.
没这她可睡不着哦
You know she can't sleep without it.
嗯  她现在在睡觉呢
Well, she's asleep now.
别再塞这玩意儿给她
Stop forcing that thing on her.
好的
Okay.
哦  你绝对不会相信今天发生的事
You're not gonna believe what happened to me today!
拉夫·劳伦公司打电话请我回去
Ralph Lauren called and gave me my job back!
-不会吧   -好奇怪啊
- No! - I mean, it was the weirdest thing.
他们先是解雇我  然后又无缘无故重新聘用我
They fire me and then out of nowhere, they just hire me back.
一定是没我就不行了
I mean, that place must just be falling apart without me!
那么  你不去巴黎了吧
So you're not going to Paris?
去呀  我还去
No, I'm still going!
什么...
What?
好吧  当路易威登公司发现
Well, when the Louis Vuitton people found out...
拉夫·劳伦公司请我回去
...that Ralph Lauren wanted me back,
他们就提高了我的报酬
they offered me more money!
罗斯  是不是太棒了
Ross, isn't that great?
我们有意买下旁边的那座房子
Hi. We're buying the house next door.
允许我们参观一下这里吗
Could we just take a look around?
当然可以
Sure,
我刚好带人来参观
I'm showing it to someone else right now,
你们进来吧
but please, look around.
我感到这是对我们房子的不忠
I feel like we're cheating on our house.
如果不忠的话  我们不也应该
If we cheat, shouldn't it
一些事情老房子不会做
be with a hot, younger house...
一个会做的年轻漂亮的房子来不忠吗
...that does stuff that our house won't do?
我们的比这里更棒
Ours is so much better!
客厅更小
This living room is smaller,
饭厅像个洞穴
the dining room looks like a cave.
真受不了
What a hole!
-你们觉得怎么样   -喜欢
- So, what do you think? - Love it!
我们本来有一位买家
We already have one offer.
楼上的女士是另一位
I think the lady upstairs will make another one.
是我们将来的邻居  他们是什么样的
They could be our neighbors. What are they like?
楼上这位女士很好
The woman upstairs is nice.
她和丈夫有2个小孩
She and her husband have two kids.
丈夫在华尔街工作  她是...
He's on Wall Street, and she's a--
哦...天...啊...
Oh... my... God!
没错
Sure.
乔伊  你想和我去...
Hey, Joey, you wanna come with me to--?
你怎么啦
Are you okay?
我为解雇艾丝特尔的事难过
Yeah, I just feel bad about firing Estelle.
她肯定伤心死了
This has gotta be killing her.
她不会因此死的
No, that wouldn't kill her.
冠状动脉栓塞有可能
A coronary embolism might.
她心都碎了  我是她唯一的客户
I don't know. She's gotta be taking it hard. I was her only client.
那个会吃纸的家伙除外
Except for this guy who eats paper.
我猜他吃的钱比挣得多
And I'm guessing he eats more money than he makes.
我明白她不是优秀的经纪人
Look, I know she's not a great agent,
但我们合作10年了
but she did stick with me for 10 years.
我要给她打电话  重新雇佣她
I'm gonna call her and hire her again.
不...  不要给她打电话
No, no, no! Don't call her.
-你等她给你打电话   -为什么
- You wait for her to call you. - Why?
耐心是通向理解的大道
Because patience is the road to understanding.
那是得到快乐的关键
Which is the key to a happy heart.
你真让人吃惊  我服了
You blow me away.
答应我  你等她给你打电话
All right, so promise you're gonna wait for her to call you?
-我答应你   -好的
- I promise. - Okay.
这意味着  从不需要有原因
And that means never having to give a reason.
这世界真小呀
What a small world!
我还没碰到过碧昂丝
And yet I never run into Beyonce.
你们认识
You two know each other?
我们是老交情了
We go way back.
在莫妮卡认识他之前
Before Monica made an honest man out of him...
钱德勒曾经是我的小甜甜
...Chandler used to be my little love muffin.
这么说  你们也要想买下一座房子
So are you guys thinking of getting this house too?
如果是要投标竞价的话
Are we gonna have a bidding war?
我可要警告你了  我是流氓我怕谁
I better warn you, I'm a toughie.
别...
Don't...
别这样
Don't do that.
其实我们打算买下隔壁那座房子
No, actually, we are buying the house next door.
为什么
Why?
我不知道为什么
I don't know why.
那就这么定了   本来我还在犹豫
Oh, that decides it, then! I was on the fence.
没想到我们会成为邻居
But knowing that you two would be our neighbors?
那我就买下来了
Now we have to get it!
艾伦  我们去定下价钱
Ellen, we're gonna talk numbers.
怎么会搞成这样
This cannot be happening.
经纪人不是说还有 另外一对夫妇有意购买吗
The realtor said another couple made an offer.
珍妮斯可能就买不成了
Maybe the Janices won't get it!
另外的夫妇可能会买下
Maybe the other couple will.
这绝不可能发生
The only way that'll happen is
除非那是希特勒夫妇
if the other couple are the Hitlers!
我们两座房子都买下来  怎么样
Okay, okay! All right, what if we get both houses?
将这里作为家庭旅馆
We can turn this one into a guesthouse!
真是好主意
That's a great idea!
我不是想招讨厌
By the way, I don't mean to sound distasteful...
但你从什么时候开始爱乱花钱了
...but when did you start crapping money?
-好呀  那你来想办法  -好啊
- You come up with an idea. - All right.
还有3个小时才签约
We've still got three hours till escrow closes on our house.
我们现在取消还来得及
We can still get out.
我们喜欢这座房子
But we love our house.
你也同样喜欢住在她隔壁吗
Will we love it so much with her next door?
她还会在这大声嚷嚷
And she's gonna be louder out here too!
讨厌的"噢...天...啊..."
Just the crickets and, "Oh... my... God!"
即使我们不买这座房子
Okay. But if we don't get this house,
她还是会在我们面前出现
she'll still show up wherever we go.
她住在这
At least if she's here,
起码不会再吓我们一跳
it eliminates the element of surprise.
你不会再听到那3个字
Never again will you have to hear the three words...
连你的蛋蛋都被吓得缩进去
...that make your balls jump back up inside your body!
我们得想想办法
Well, we have to do something.
不能就让她住在隔壁
We can't have her living next door.
嗯  这也会
Oh, that does it too.
谁
Who is it?
是我  罗恩
It's me. Ron.
我知道瑞秋拒绝你了
Look, I know Rachel turned you down...
不过我有一个法子能让她会来
...but I think there's a way you might be able to get her to come back.
请你别见怪
This may surprise you,
重新聘用已经解雇的员工  不是我主要的工作
but rehiring fired employees is not my main job.
先听我说
Just hear me out.
给她提高薪酬  你认为怎么样
How would you feel about offering her a raise?
不好  罗恩
Not good, Ron.
可能我会说服你
Perhaps I can persuade you.
你希望送给你儿子
What if you could give your son...
这么一只恐龙蛋复制品吗
...this genuine pterodactyl egg replica.
哇  这很不错呀
Wow! That's pretty cool.
这么说  我们成交了
So? Do we have a deal?
-好的  你成功了  -太好了
- Okay, you got it. - Yes! Yes!
这会让我很受欢迎
This is gonna make me very popular.
相信我  女士都喜欢它
Believe me, the ladies, they love it.
我指的是我儿子
I meant with my son.
对  女士对它不感兴趣
Good, because the ladies, not so much.
乔伊  我是阿尔·则布克  那个吃纸的人
Joey, this is Al Zebooker, the guy who eats paper.
相信你听说了艾丝特尔过世的消息
I'm sure you've heard that Estelle passed away.
我通知你参加追悼会
I wanted to let you know there's a memorial for her...
在韦斯特赛德教堂  明天10点
...at the Westside Chapel tomorrow at 1O.
希望你能来
Hope you can make it.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
-你好  -乔伊  我是艾丝特尔
- Hello? - Joey, it's Estelle.
艾丝特尔
Estelle?
我打电话是要告诉你
Yeah, I wanted to call and tell you
我没有因为你解雇我而感到伤心
that there's no hard feelings for firing me.
好的  真难以置信你会打电话给我
Okay. I just-- I can't believe you're calling me.
我觉得我不应该贸然造访
I didn't think I should just drop by.
不  不要来访
No, no! Don't drop by! Don't drop by!
总之  你做了你必须做的是  我没意见
Anyway, you did what you had to do. I'm okay.
能问你个问题吗
Can I ask you something?
你那边怎么样
What's it like there?
还凑合
It's all right.
我要挂了  祝你好运
Look, kiddo, I gotta go.
你会飞黄腾达的
Good luck with the career. You're gonna be huge!
谢谢你艾丝特尔  再见
Thanks for everything, Estelle. Bye.
不在服务区  那肯定的
"Out of area." Boy, I'll say!
我刚才打给西德了
Well, I just talked to Sid.
我们要买下这座房子
We are definitely putting in an offer on the house.
一定会成功的
And I'll bet we get it!
希特勒夫妇肯定会很失望
The Hitlers will be so disappointed.
我要先走了  帮我跟莫妮卡说再见
All right, I gotta run. Tell Monica I say goodbye.
我们回头见  邻居
I'll see you later, neighbor.
等等
Wait!
我想告诉你  你住在这里我很开心
I just want you to know that I'm so happy you're going to be here.
噢  我也是
Oh, me too!
因为这样
Because...
这样...
...that way...
我们就能再续前缘
...we can pick up where we left off.
我一直都爱着你
I never stopped loving you.
-噢...天...  -停...
- Oh... my-- - Yeah...
我想你
I want you.
我爱你
I need you.
我要你
I must have you,
珍妮斯·利特曼·高妮科·尼豪金斯丁
Janice Litman-Goralnik ne Hosenstein.
钱德勒  你在说什么啊
Chandler, what are you talking about?
你现在住在隔壁  我们会每天在一起
Now that you live next door, we can be together every day.
西德和莫妮卡根本不会察觉
Sid and Monica never have to know a thing.
我不知道该说什么
I don't know what to say.
很显然  我们之间还有热情
I mean, you know, obviously we have this heat between us.
很显然
Obviously.
但我爱我的丈夫
But I love my husband.
我也知道你爱你的妻子
And I know you love your wife.
我现在认为我不应该买这座房子
I don't think we should get this house now.
别这么说  别打破我们的美梦
Don't say that. Don't dangle the dream and take it away.
钱德勒  我们其中必须有一个人立场要坚定
Chandler, one of us has got to be strong.
我知道
I understand.
尽管
Although....
最后就软弱一次吧
Maybe just one last moment of weakness.
再见了  钱德勒·宾
Goodbye, Chandler Bing.
不会再出现啦
They're never coming down now!
-嘿  -嘿
- Hi. - Hi!
嘿  你肯定不会相信今天的事
You are never going to believe what happened to me today.
是什么
What?
拉夫·劳伦公司又打电话来了
Ralph Lauren called, again,
而且他们给我更高的报酬
and they offered me more money.
- 真的吗   - 是的  真的太古怪了
- They did? - Yes! It was the weirdest thing.
泽尔纳打给我  说愿意以任何代价请我回去
Zelner called me and said, "We will do anything we can to get you back."
还说我应该为此感谢罗恩
And that I should thank some "Ron."
可我连他是哪个部门的都不知道
I don't even know what department that guy's in!
-那么  你决定要怎么做  -我接受了
- So, what are you gonna do? - Well, I took it!
这太好了  你会留在纽约
That's great! So you're staying in New York!
你高兴吗
You're excited, right?
是的  报酬很优厚
You know, the money's great.
-这样选择会容易些  -对呀
- It's certainly the easier choice. - Right.
我本来是盼望着去巴黎的吗  当然
But, you know, I mean, was I looking forward to going to Paris? Sure.
为能在时尚之都工作而感到兴奋
Was I excited about working in the fashion capital of the world?
哦  太棒了
Oh, absolutely.
不过  这样也不错
Yeah, but you know, this is....
重新回到原来的工作
It's fine. I'm fine going back to a job where I've pretty much...
一个为之付出所有努力的工作
...gotten everything out of it that I possibly can.
我不知道
I had no idea--
我不知道你为巴黎如此着迷
I had no idea you were so excited about Paris.
你说过你感到害怕
I mean, you said you were scared.
我想这是良性的害怕
I mean, it was "good" scared, though, you know?
当我搬来纽约时  我感到害怕
I mean, like "when I moved to New York" scared.
当我发现怀上艾玛时  我感到害怕
Or "when I found out I was gonna have Emma" scared.
这很不错啦  能行的
But this is fine. This is gonna be good.
你应该去
You should go.
什么
What?
那是你希望做到的  去吧
It's what you want. You should go.
你真的这么认为吗
You really think so?
真的
I really do.
可是我已经答应泽尔纳我会回去
But I already told Zelner that I would come back.
我相信他会理解的
I'm sure he'll understand.
好的  我就这么定了  我要去巴黎
All right. All right! I'm gonna do it! I'm gonna go to Paris!
-好啊  -好啊
- Yeah. - Yeah.
好啊  我要去巴黎
I'm going to Paris!
-谢谢你  罗斯  -是啊
- Thank you, Ross. - Yeah, yeah.
我太高兴了
Oh, I'm so happy.
那我也高兴
Then I'm happy too.
谢谢你们的到来
Thank you all for coming.
我们相聚在此怀念一位优秀的经纪人
We're here today to pay our respects to a wonderful agent...
一位美丽的女性
...and a beautiful woman.
内在美
Inside.
作为艾丝特尔仅有的两位客户
As Estelle's only two clients,
我们有话要说
we would like to say a few words.
哥们  我的讲稿上哪去了
Dude, where's my speech?
这么做很有趣
That is entertaining.
各位  这是阿尔·则布克
Al Zebooker, everybody!